
let $questions = [{
        "question" : "Planning is the intelligent estimate of resources required to perform a predefined project successfully at a future date within a defined environment.",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "NA",
        "d": "NA",
        "answer": "a"
},       
{
        "question": "What attributes DOES NOT make planning for software project unique?",
        "a": "Functionality is the primary output",
        "b": "Productivity and quality are dependent on humans",
        "c": "Output is physical.",
        "d": "Software engineering tools have limited predictability",
        "answer": "c"
},         
{
        "question" : "What is NOT a key feature of the project management plan?",
        "a": "Estimate: predict status of project",
        "b": "Resources: machines, personnel, materials, etc.",
        "c": "Dates: milestones, end date, etc.",
        "d": "Best practices: things learnt from other projects",
        "answer": "d"
},         
{
        "question" : "What is not a best practice in software project planning",
        "a": "Creating a work register",
        "b": "Perform variance analysis to uncover the difference between actual and planned behaviour",
        "c": "Norms for planning where knowledge repository is important",
        "d": "Following a process driven approach",
        "answer": "a"
},  
{
        "question" : "What factors can result in scope creep",
        "a": "Changing user requirements ",
        "b": "Poorly defined scope statements ",
        "c": "Business analyst errors or underestimation ",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "d"
},  
{
        "question" : "How can project effort increase?",
        "a": "scope creep",
        "b": "low productivity",
        "c": "poor morale",
        "d": "all of the above",
        "answer": "d"
},  
{
        "question" : "What is not one of the five questions of service definition",
        "a": "Service description",
        "b": "Service delivery",
        "c": "Service provision",
        "d": "Service support",
        "answer": "c"
},  
{
        "question" : "What does the work break down structure consist of?",
        "a": "Start milestone",
        "b": "Internal mileston",
        "c": "End milestone",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "d"
},  
{
        "question" : "What is not a benefit of prince 2",
        "a": "Allows early warning and detection of problems.",
        "b": "Consistent set of benchmarks, processes, and procedures.",
        "c": "Quick iteration sprints of the project",
        "d": "Official certification and qualification scheme for professionals.",
        "answer": "c"
},  
{
        "question" : "What is NOT a characteristic of Agile development?",
        "a": "Daily feedback and self directed team",
        "b": "Hard touch",
        "c": "Open information",
        "d": "Guiding information",
        "answer": "b"
},  
{
        "question" : "Poor kick-off meetings is a common pitfall of software project initiation?",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "NA",
        "d": "NA",
        "answer": "b"
},  
{
        "question" : "Which of the following is not considered a criteria for success?",
        "a": "The project was on cost",
        "b": "The project was on time",
        "c": "The software specification and the user requirements were met",
        "d": "Minimal change requests from the client",
        "answer": "c"
},
{
        "question" : "Project managers have to assess the risks that may affect a project.",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "None",
        "d": "Both",
        "answer": "b"
},  
{
        "question" : "Which of the following is not considered as a risk in project management?",
        "a": "Specification delays",
        "b": "Product competition",
        "c": "Testing",
        "d": "Staff turnover",
        "answer": "c"
},  
{
        "question" : "The process each manager follows during the life of a project is known as:",
        "a": "Project Management",
        "b": "Manager life cycle",
        "c": "Project Management Life Cycle",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "c"
},  
{
        "question" : "A general statement of objectives is the major cause of failed software efforts.",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "None",
        "d": "Both",
        "answer": "a"
},  
{
        "question" : "Requirements traceability is one of the most important part requirement management. It may also be referred to as the heart of requirement management.",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "None",
        "d": "Both",
        "answer": "a"
},  
{
        "question" : "According to a statistical report: 'over 30% of all software projects are cancelled before completion and over 70% of the remainder fail to deliver expected features'. What must be the reason for such a situation?",
        "a": "Poor change management",
        "b": "Poor requirements management",
        "c": "Poor quality control",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "b"
},  
];
